A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Oscar Harkavy FA623
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Oscar Harkavy
1960-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA623
28.5 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh, 1974-1980
  - ICDDR -- Ford Foundation Recommendations for Grant Action and Chronology of ICDDR (and Ford Foundation Letter, April 1, 1980 article), 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Meeting of Interim International Committee to Assist in Establishing the ICDDR, Bangladesh (Geneva, February 13-14, 1979) -- Memo and Summary Report (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Meeting of the Consultative Group on the International Centre for Diarrheal Disease Research, Bangladesh (Geneva, June 6, 1980), Jun 1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Correspondence Concerning Potential Board Members, 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR -- Correspondence with World Health Organization (WHO, Geneva), 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR and Cholera Research Laboratory (CRL) -- Correspondence, incl. Family Planning and General Health-Related Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR and Cholera Research Laboratory (CRL) -- Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDRB/CRL/International Center for Health Research -- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - CRL -- Memoranda, Correspondence, Dec 1977-Feb 1978 (Box 1)
  - CRL/ICDDR -- Annual Reports (1976-1979), Index to Publications and Presentations, Newsletter, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR/CRL/International Institute for Research on Health, Nutrition and Population (IIRHNP) -- Correspondence, RGA, Reports, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - CRL -- Reports, Notes Re: Program Activity and Creation of International Center for Health Research, 1978 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR, Bangladesh -- Reports, Memoranda Re: Family Planning, Bangladesh Consultancies, etc., 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - ICDDR, Bangladesh/CRL -- Reports Re: Creation of ICDDR, Bangladesh Family Planning and Population Programs, Meetings, Research, etc., 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Joint Ford Foundation/ Population Council Asia Regional Population Meeting (Dacca), Apr 1976 (Box 1)
  - "A Prospective Study of Birth Interval Dynamics in Rural Bangladesh" -- Report, Ford Foundation Dacca Office by Lincoln Chen, et al., Feb 1974 (Box 1)
  - "What's the Use of a Demonstration Project?" -- Report, Ford Foundation Dacca Office by Colin McCord, Nov 1976 (Box 1)
  - "Control of Diarrheal Disease Morbidity and Mortality: Some Strategic Issues" by Lincoln Chen Prepared for the Workshop on Effective Interventions to Reduce Infections, Jun 1977 (Box 1)
- Reproductive Sciences, 1974-1980
  File Plan
  original numbering preserved
  - 1. Reproductive Science Initiative, Feb 1976-Jul 1980 (Box 2)
  - 2. Reproductive Research Policy, Mar 3, 1977-Oct 25, 1978 (Box 2)
  - 3. Reproductive Science -- Foundation Consortium Materials, Aug 1976-Aug 1978 (Box 2)
  - 4. Oscar Harkavy Paper, "Funding of Contraceptive Research" Presented Before Royal Society, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 5. International Committee for Contraception Research -- Meetings, May-Oct 1980 (Box 2)
  - 6. Contraceptive Safety File, 1978-1980 (Box 2)
  - 7. Miscellaneous Background Papers Re: Population/Health/Development, Jun 1975-Dec 1976 (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Patents, Liability -- Contraceptive Development, 1971 (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Patent Policy, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
  - 8. Medical Ethics -- Research Involving Human Subjects, Safety Protocols, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
  - 9. Greep Report/Contraception/Reproductive Sciences -- Contraception: Science, Technology, and Application -- Proceedings of a Symposium, 1979 (Box 2)
  - 9. Greep Report/Contraception/Reproductive Sciences -- Responses to Greep Advisory Committee Meeting and to Published Report, Feb 1975-Dec 1978 (Box 2)
  - 10. UNFPA -- Consultation on Population Assistance Coordination (Geneva, March 15-16, 1979), Mar 15-16, 1979 (Box 2)
- International Review Group of Social Science Research on Population and Development (IRG), 1975-1981
  - 1. International Review Group (IRG) Draft Report; Oscar Harkavy Paper on IRG -- Donor's Viewpoint, Mar 1979 (Box 3)
  - 2. International Review Group (IRG) Final Report -- Related Correspondence and Reports, Jan 1977-Nov 1980 (Box 3)
  - 3a. International Review Group -- The World Bank -- Report of the External Advisory Panel on Population, Aug 1976 (Box 3)
  - 3b. International Review Group -- Working papers Leading up to Grant for International Review Group (Urquidi and Miro), Mar 1976 (Box 3)
  - 3c. International Review Group -- First IRG Workshop on Research Priorities for Population Policy (Colombo) -- Draft Summary Report, Apr 1978 (Box 3)
  - 3d. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- Demographic Requirements of Fertility Control Technology; Romanian Anti-Abortion Decree, 1978 (Box 3)
  - 3e. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- Social Science Research for Population Policy, Jun 1977 (Box 3)
  - 3f. International Review Group -- Bernard Berelson -- "Social Science Research on Population" and Other IRG Documents and Related Papers, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - 4. Gavin Jones -- Social Science Research Report on East and Southeast Asia -- Draft Report for IRG, Mexico City, Jan 1978 (Box 3)
  - 5. Responses to Berelson-Mauldin Request for "New Efforts" Descriptions; Berelson Paper of January 1976, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - 6. IRG Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - 7. International Review Group of Social Science Research on Popultaion and Development -- Carmen Miro -- Reports, Workshop Materials, Program Statements and Status Updates, 1975-1978 (Box 3)
  - 8. United Nations Fund for Population Activities (UNFPA) -- Correspondence, Apr 1970-1981 (Box 3)
  - 9. "Population in the Year 2000" -- An ODC Seminar on the 10th Anniversary of the Establishment of the UNFPA, Nov 1979 (Box 3)
  - 10. United Nations Consultative Meeting on the National Household Survey Capability Programme, Jun 21-22, 1979 (Box 3)
- Population and Health Files, 1973-1981
  - 1. December Strategy Paper Re: Population; Background Reports and Notes, Comments Re: Population and Development, 1976 (Box 4)
  - 2. Comments on Robert McNamara's Address by Population Office Staff and David Bell, Mar 21, 1977 (Box 4)
  - 3. The Foundation's Strategy for Work on Population (Ford Foundation information paper, June 1977); Health, Nutrition, and Population Information Paper (Dec 1979), 1977-1979 (Box 4)
  - 4. International Division Reorganization and Related Papers -- Population Program, Representatives' Meeting, etc., Jan-Sep 1980 (Box 4)
  - 5. Meeting with Franklin Thomas Re: Population Office, Jul 16, 1979 (Box 4)
  - 6. Population -- Other Donor Data, Apr 1973-Jun 1980 (Box 4)
  - 7. Working Group on Nutrition Materials -- incl. Reports Re: Nutrition Programming, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - 8. Working Group on Nutrition and Incidental Papers Re: Health, Nutrition, and Population; Chafkin Correspondence, Sep 1979-Jul 1980 (Box 4)
  - 9. Nutrition Papers, Sep 1976-Feb 1979 (Box 4)
  - 10. Washington Follow-On -- Materials on DHEW Budget, FY 1979; Bundy-Kretchmer Notes; Notes, Proposals, Reports Re: Reproductive Science and Contraception, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
- Bellagio Population Conferences, 1970-1971
  Arrangement
  Chronological
  - Bellagio I (April 1970) -- Participants List, Papers (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II (June 1971) -- Planning Materials, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- Agenda, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio II -- "The Commitment of Leaders" by David Bell, incl. Drafts, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Interim Committee -- Minutes of Meeting, Sep 10, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Group File -- Population Program Proposals, Meeting Notes, etc., 1970 (Box 5)
  - International Population Research Institutes and Bellagio Population Group Interim Committee Notes, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Recommendations/Responses to Bellagio Population Group Steering Committee Re: Population Activities Proposals, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (1/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (2/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Conference Proposals, Reports (3/3), 1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Group -- Memoranda, Reports, etc. (1/2), 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Bellagio Population Group -- Memoranda, Reports, etc., 1970-1971 (Box 5)
- Bellagio Population Conferences, 1971-1977
  - Bellagio II, Jun 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Reports, Abstracts of Reports Submitted to the Conference and Summary of Conference, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Participants List, Submitted Proposals List, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio Steering Committee Meeting -- Delivery Systems, Apr 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio Steering Committee Meeting -- Social Research/Population Policy, Apr 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Comments on Papers, Mar-Jun 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II -- Agenda, Status Reports, Information Papers, etc., 1971 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio II and III -- Correspondence with Dr. Allan Barnes and Others Re: Bellagio Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Social Research and Population Policy Summary and Recommendations, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Population Conference -- Progress Reports for Afternoon Session (May 11, 1973) (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Population Conference -- Summary and Projections, May 12, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- "The Social Sciences and Development" -- Conference Papers, Feb 12-14, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- Third Conference on Population -- Working Papers (published volume), Jun 1974 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio III -- "Priorities for Work on the World Population Problem: Bellagio III" -- Information Paper, Jun 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bellagio IV -- Seminar Held at Ford Foundation Preparatory to OH and DEB Attendance at Bellagio IV (Denmark, June 6-9, 1977), Jun 2, 1977 (Box 6)
- Population Papers, Conferences, 1968-1970
  - Development Centre (of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development) -- First Meeting on Population -- Reports, Information Papers, Dec 3-5, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Commercial Distribution of Contraceptives -- Meeting at the Ford Foundation (April 28-29, 1969) Re: Marketing and Distribution of Contraceptives, Apr 28-29, 1969 (Box 7)
  - India Population Meeting (Millbrook, September 23-24, 1969) -- Memoranda, Reports (Box 7)
  - Population/Family Planning Evaluation Conference (Marino, Italy, April 1970) -- Evaluation Materials, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - UNDP Population Program -- Possible Committee Members, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Population Crisis Committee -- September 30, 1969 Meeting -- Re: Population Education Campaign (Box 7)
  - "The Foundation's Work on Population" -- Information Paper, Sep 1970 (Box 7)
  - Advisors on Family Planning in India -- Memoranda, Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (DHEW) -- Policy Review Report Re: Family Planning and Population Research, 1969 (Box 7)
  - DHEW-AID Population Research File, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Conference (Paris) (1/2), Nov 17-21, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) Conference (Paris) (2/2), Nov 17-21, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Domestic Family Planning -- Memoranda, Report, Grants List, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Congressman Bush -- Requesting Harkavy Appearance Before Congress Re: Population Problem and Tax Legislation, Testimony Included, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Nixon Letter (by Harkavy) Drafts and Memoranda -- Funding Population Research and Work, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - UCLA-Harbor General Hospital Ford Foundation Training and Research Program -- Transfer of Program and Electron Microscope to USC, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Tax Reform Act of 1969 -- Ford Foundation Response to Act, Provisions Affecting Foundation Grantmaking, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Rand/World Bank February 19, 1969 Meeting, Feb 19, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Rand Proposal Materials Re: Population Control, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Investigation of Training Opportunities in Demography and Economic Development, 1968-1970 (Box 7)
  - Press Conference (April 1, 1970) with Science Press and Grantees in Population Field, Apr 1, 1970 (Box 7)
- Evaluation Conference, Population Papers, 1967-1975
  - Evaluation Conference -- Monday, Apr 20, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Tuesday (1/2), Apr 21, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Tuesday (2/2), Apr 21, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Wednesday (1/2), Apr 22, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Wednesday (2/2), Apr 22, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Thursday (1/2), Apr 23, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Thursday (2/2), Apr 23, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Evaluation Conference -- Friday, Apr 24, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Atlanta -- Grady Hospital, 1967 (Box 8)
  - (Office of) Education, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Lee, Philip -- Memos, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Program Notes Re: Family Planning, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Hardin, Lowell -- Information, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Hathaway, Dale -- Lecture and Program Participation at Stanford University and University of California, Davis Re: Agriculture and Nutrition, Apr 1975 (Box 8)
  - India Field Office, 1969-1971 (Box 8)
  - International Rice Research Institute -- Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Pakistan, 1972 (Box 8)
  - French Language Resource Base -- Family Planning Program, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Muscat Proposal -- Stimulating Demand for Family Planning, 1975 (Box 8)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development Interagency Collaboration Meeting, Jan 9-10, 1975 (Box 8)
- Population Papers, Trip Files, 1967-1974
  - DHEW Report, "Implementing DHEW Policy on Family Planning and Population" by Oscar Harkavy (September 5 and 18, 1967) and Working Papers, Sep 1967 (Box 9)
  - Family Planning Reports and Memo -- Public Health Service and Planned Parenthood, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation Memos Re: Social Science Research and Development, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation/Harvard University Report/Review Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development -- Africa (1/2), 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Ford Foundation/Harvard University Report/Review Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development -- Africa (2/2), 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Funding Aspects Re: Support of Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development (Box 9)
  - National Center for Health Statistics, 1967 (Box 9)
  - National and Geographic Regions and Representatives -- Funding Aspects, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Population Studies Proposals and Reports (International), 1974 (Box 9)
  - Regional Visits -- Miscellaneous Re: Family Planning Programs, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Report on Family Planning -- Correspondence Re: Report Planning, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Requests for Essays Re: Reproductive Biology and Contraceptive Development, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Strategy Paper Materials, Jul 16, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Strategy Paper (Population) -- Draft Comments, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Welfare Administration -- Incl. Departmental Expenditures on Family Planning, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
  - Harkavy's Trip -- Asia, Jul 1968 (Box 9)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Harkavy -- Asia Trip, Jul 1-25, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Asia Trip Notes -- Pakistan, India, Indonesia, Aug 1969 (Box 9)
  - Pakistan, India, Indonesia Trip -- Planning Memoranda, Itinerary..., Aug 1969 (Box 9)
  - North Africa Trip, Jan 1970 (Box 9)
  - Trip Report -- Hawaii, Indonesia, Bangkok, India and Memoranda/Reports Re: Population Problems in Asia and the Pacific, 1971 (Box 9)
- Trip, Conference and Population Papers, 1967-1979
  Original order preserved
  - Trip -- Bellagio, India, Pakistan -- Miscellaneous Documents, May 1975 (Box 10)
  - Asia -- Trip Notes and Miscellaneous Materials, Oct 1977 (Box 10)
  - Bangkok, Thailand Field Office, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Trip Notes -- Visit of Harkavy, Saunders, Nagel to Brazil and Mexico, Mar 6-19, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Brazilian Population Studies Project, 1975-1978 (Box 10)
  - PISPAL, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Informal Trip Notes, Nigeria, Sep 24-29, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Paper, "Population and Family Planning in Mexico", Jul 1978 (Box 10)
  - Folder VI -- Brazil Trip Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Asian Parasite Control Organization -- 3rd Conference (Hotel New Otani, Tokyo), Oct 20-25, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Mr. Harkavy's Santiago Trip, Apr 1967 (Box 10)
- Population Papers, 1970-1976
  - Board of Trustees Meetings Re: Trustee Planning Project and "The Hungry, Crowded, Competitive World" (OH paper not in folder), 1976 (Box 11)
  - Elsinore Population Meeting Re: Reproductive Biology (1/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - Elsinore Population Meeting Re: Reproductive Biology (2/2), 1972 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Meetings -- Population and Social Science, incl. Bellagio, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Population Crisis Article (NY Times) and Population Commission Memo, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Population Studies Centers -- Funding, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Preterm -- Re: Manuals for Abortion Services Programs, 1972-1977 (Box 11)
  - Social Science and Management Research on Population -- Asia Meeting, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Social Science, Demographic, and Management Research and June 29, 1971 Discussion (Box 11)
  - Social Science Research -- Population and Development -- Report ("The Volume") -- Comments, Summary, etc., 1974 (Box 11)
  - Trudy Berkowitz -- Review of Population Studies Centers, 1973 (Box 11)
  - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill -- Carolina Population Center -- Ford Foundation Visit, Nov 1976 (Box 11)
- Population Papers, 1960-1981
  - Association of American Medical Colleges -- Mr. Bundy's Speech (March 23, 1969), Also Notes Re: India's Population Problem, 1969-1974 (Box 12)
  - Bundy, McGeorge -- Address to AAMC, Ford Foundation "Population" Policy Paper, 1963-1969 (Box 12)
  - Child Growth, Health, and Infant Survival -- Proposals, Reports, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Immigration, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Immigration Policy, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Immigration and Refugees -- Information Papers/Reports, 1980 (Box 12)
  - International Immigration -- Asian Migration to the Middle East, 1979 (Box 12)
  - International Migration, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
  - International Migration -- Solicited Research Program, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - McLaughlin, Robert -- Population Grants, Graduate Work at Princeton, etc., 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Medical School, Hospital Program -- Population Council -- Re: Family Planning, 1967 (Box 12)
  - Middle East Research Awards Program -- Guillaume de Spoelberch, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Owolabi/Drysdale -- Health, Family Planning in Africa, 1978-1980 (Box 12)
  - "Plans for the Future" -- A Statement by the Trustees of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Population Paper -- "Population Growth and Family Planning in Kenya" and Chronology of Developments of U.S. Population Policy, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Population/Resources Papers, 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - "The Social Sciences and Population Policy - A Survey" by Edwin Driver -- Report to Population Office, Feb 1970 (Box 12)
  - Technical Assistance Career Program Memorandum and Population Problems Board of Trustees Docket Item, 1960 (Box 12)
  - UNFPA Contraceptive Development Project -- Meeting, Oct 15, 1981 (Box 12)
  - West Africa Research Agenda -- Meeting with Professor Mabogunje Re: Interrelationship between Population and Development, Feb 27, 1978 (Box 12)
- Population Papers, 1974-1980
  - Middle East Workshop on Multivariate Analysis (Istanbul), 1980 (Box 13)
  - Rockefeller/Ford Competition, 1976-1978 (Box 13)
  - Rockefeller/Ford Competition and Subsequent Social Science Activities -- Harkavy Copies of Reports, Memoranda, 1978-1980 (Box 13)
  - Social Science DAP, Jan-Aug 1980 (Box 13)
  - United Nations World Population Conference (Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974) (1/2) (Box 13)
  - United Nations World Population Conference (Bucharest, Aug 19-30, 1974) (2/2) (Box 13)
- Population Council and Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1963-1981
  - Population Council Evaluation -- Financial/Hayes, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- ICCR/Steelman, Ryan, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- IP/Field Responses, Lyle Saunders, 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council Evaluation -- Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council External Evaluations, Aug-Dec 1973 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Materials, 1963-1967 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Policy Review -- Miscellaneous Drafts, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Semi-Annual Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Status Report, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Miscellaneous Memoranda (1/2), Dec 1974-Jan 1975 (Box 14)
  - Population Council -- Miscellaneous Memoranda (2/2), 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Population and Family Planning Reports, Memoranda, Project Lists, etc., 1979 (Box 14)
  - Fred Jaffe and the Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1968-1977 (Box 14)
  - Alan Guttmacher Institute, 1980-1981 (Box 14)
- Chronological Correspondence, Information Papers, Conference, 1977-1981
  - Chrons, Jan 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Feb 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Mar 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Apr 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, May 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Jun 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Jul 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Aug 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Sep 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Oct 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Nov 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chrons, Dec 1984 (Box 15)
  - Report on Affirmative Action, Mar 1978 (Box 15)
  - International Division's Women's Program -- Information Paper, Jan 1979 (Box 15)
  - Ford Foundation Programs for Women -- Information Paper, Dec 1979 (Box 15)
  - Ford Foundation Programs for Women -- Plans and Budgets for FY1980-1981, Mar 1980 (Box 15)
  - Review of Research on Women in Agriculture and Rural Development, Oct 1980 (Box 15)
  - Survey of International Funding for the Advancement of Women, [1978] (Box 15)
  - Correspondence re: Women's Activities, Dec 1979-Feb 1981 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence on Women's Issues, 1974-1978 (Box 15)
  - Bellagio Conference Materials -- Population Office Annual Reports and Supporting Documents, 1966-1973 (Box 15)
  - Bellagio Conference on Health and Population in Developing Countries, Apr 18-21, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Bellagio Conference on Health and Population in Developing Countries -- Agenda and Discussion Papers, Apr 18-21, 1979 (Box 15)